Finding aid for the Razorcake/Gorsky Press, Inc. Records LSC.2284
UCLA Library Special Collections
Razorcake/Gorsky Press, Inc. records
1989-2016
2001-2016
UCLA Library Special Collections
Taylor, Todd
LSC.2284
9.6 linear feet (5 boxes, 3 shoeboxes, 3 record cartons, 1 oversize flat box, 1 map folder)
Razorcake is a Los Angeles-based punk rock fanzine established in 2001 and published by Sean Carswell and Todd Taylor. The collection includes zine issues, microcassettes of interviews, and punk memorabilia and ephemera.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains processed audiovisual materials. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Todd Taylor, 2015, 2016.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9978158203606533
Biography/History
Gorsky Press is an independent book publisher based out of Los Angeles, California, founded in 1999. Razorcake is the magazine arm of Razorcake/Gorsky Press, Inc., launched in 2001 by former staff and writers for the defunct zine Flipside. It features interviews, columns, and reviews, mainly focused on DIY (do-it-yourself) punk rock music. Razorcake is the first and only official non-profit punk rock fanzine in America. It is published by Sean Carswell and Todd Taylor.
Scope and Content
Collection includes a near-complete run of Razorcake fanzine along with microcassettes containing interviews conducted with punk bands and artists. Also includes a small amount of punk memorabilia and ephemera which belonged to Todd Taylor.
Organization and Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Audio Interviews, 2000-2010
Series 2: Razorcake Fanzine Issues, 2001-2016
Series 3: Memorabilia and Ephemera, 1989-2015
Metadata Rights Declaration
Finding aid description and metadata in this record are licensed under a Creative Commons Public Domain Designation (CC0 1.0 Universal). See LSC's Metadata Rights Statement for more information.
Razorcake/Gorsky Press, Inc. -- Archives
- Audio Interviews, 2000-2010
  Scope and Content
  140 microcassettes containing interviews conducted with punk bands and artists for Razorcake. Also includes several interviews conducted by Todd Taylor for Thrasher Magazine.
  Organization and Arrangement
  Tapes are arranged alphabetically.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  SERIES CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
  - ADZ, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Against Me!, 2003 November 11 (Box 1)
    Henry Fonda Theater, Los Angeles, CA
  - Against Me!: Tom Gabel (Laura Jane Grace), 2004 October 8 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    DVD interview.
  - Against Me!, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Against Me!, 2000s (Box 3)
  - Alkaline Trio, 2001 April 2 (Box 1)
    Phone interview. Date on insert reads 5/02/01.
  - Almighty Do Me a Favor (ADMAF), 2004 November 11 (Box 1)
    Razorcake HQ
  - Apocalypse Hoboken, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Arfons, Art, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Arrivals, 2002 July (Box 1)
    924 Gilman Street, Berkeley, CA. Interview by Megan Pants and Todd Taylor.
  - At the Drive-In (ATDI), 2000s (Box 1)
  - Atom and His Package, 2001 June 14 (Box 1)
  - Atom and His Package, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Avail: Tim Barry, 2000 September (Box 1)
    Phone interview for Aquarian
  - Avail, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Bad Religion, 2000s (Box 1)
    Insert label reads: Bad Religion 1. No second tape present in collection.
  - Bag, Alice, 2004 September 18 (Box 1)
  - Baseball Furies, 2000s (Box 1)
  - The BellRays, 2000s (Box 3)
  - Bent Out of Shape, 2005 August 10 (Box 1)
    Taco Beach, Long Beach, CA
  - Billy Reese Peters: Aaron Lay, 2004 March 29 (Box 1)
  - Billy Reese Peters, 2004 December 7 (Box 1)
  - Bingenheimer, Rodney, 2001 September 25 (Box 1)
    Club Tempest, Los Angeles, CA
  - Blazing Haley, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Bloodhag, 2001 March (Box 1)
    Al's Bar, Los Angeles, CA
  - Bloodhag, 2006 May (Box 1)
    2 microcassettes.
  - Bloodhag, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Boris, 2000s (Box 3)
    Handwritten on opposite side of tape: Rev. Nørb
  - Broken Bottles, 2003 February (Box 1)
    BB's house, San Juan Capistrano, CA
  - Causey Way, 2001 January 18 (Box 1)
    Spaceland, Los Angeles, CA
  - Colver, Ed, 2000s (Box 1)
  - The Crowd, 2000s (Box 1)
  - D.O.A., 2000s (Box 1)
  - Dead to Me, 2008 May 20 (Box 1)
    Chain Reaction, Anaheim, CA
  - Diana, Mike, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Dillinger Four (D4): 2002 Tour (Box 1)
  - Dillinger Four (D4): Paddy, 2002 May 14 (Box 1)
    Phone interview.
  - Dillinger Four (D4), 2000s (Box 1)
  - Dirtnap, Ken, 2004 July 19 (Box 1)
  - Divsion of Laura Lee, 2002 April 12 (Box 1)
  - Down by Law, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Dragge, Fletcher (Pennywise), 2000s (Box 1)
  - Eddie Current Suppression Ring (ECSR): Mikey Young, 2010 January 26 (Box 1)
  - The Ends, 2004 March 18 (Box 1)
    South by Southwest (SXSW), Austin, TX
  - Epoxies, 2002 September 12 (Box 1)
    The Garage, Los Angeles, CA. Interview by Todd Taylor for Thrasher Magazine.
  - Epoxies, 2002 (Box 1)
    The Garage, Los Angeles, CA. Interview by Megan Pants.
  - F-Minus: Brad Logan, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Fat Wreck Chords: Fat Mike and Erin Burkett, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Feederz, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Fixtures, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Fucked Up, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Gain, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Gaza Strippers, 2000s (Box 1)
    Handwritten on side B of cassette: Me First
  - Giant Haystacks, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Good Riddance, 2001 Novemeber 18 (Box 1)
  - Grabass Charlestons, 2003 July (Box 2)
    Highland Park, CA
  - Grand Theft Audio (GTA), 2000s (Box 2)
    Refers to Grand Theft Audio record label in Glendale, CA.
  - Haints, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Headline Records: Jean Luc Gaudry, 2002 November 18 (Box 2)
  - Headline Records: Jean Luc Gaudry, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Hopeless Records: Louis Posen, 2000s (Box 2)
    Side B labeled record reviews.
  - Hot Snakes, 2004 October 2 (Box 2)
  - Hot Water Music, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Human Alert, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Kerr, Tim, 2004 May 21 (Box 2)
  - Kerr, Tim, 2004 October (Box 2)
  - Killer Dreamer, 2008 May 5 (Box 2)
  - Knockout Pills, 2003 March 9 (Box 2)
    Razorcake HQ. Interview for Thrasher Magazine.
  - Leatherface: Frankie Stubbs, 2008 May 20 (Box 2)
    The Sunset Bar alley, Anaheim, CA
  - The Locust, 2001 January 3 (Box 2)
    The Smell, Los Angeles, CA
  - Man or Astro-man? (MOAM?), 2000s (Box 3)
  - Marked Men, 2004 March 21 (Box 2)
    Beerland alley, Austin, TX
  - Maximum rocknroll (MRR), 2000s (Box 3)
  - Me First and the Gimme Gimmes, 2000s (Box 2)
    Handwritten on tape label: Dooger. Refers to filmmaker Doug Cawker.
    Possible that recording contains interviews with both, or case may be mislabeled.
  - Me First and the Gimme Gimmes, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Mea Culpa, 2004 April 11 (Box 2)
  - Measure, 2009 January 9 (Box 2)
  - NOFX: Fat Mike, 2006 July 11 (Box 2)
  - Observers, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Ohanesian, Liz, 2000s (Box 3)
  - Only Crime, 2004 August 11 (Box 2)
  - The Orphans, 2003 July 23 (Box 2)
    Wade's house, Long Beach, CA
  - Out Cold, 2002 April 24 (Box 2)
    Falafel Palace, Boston, MA
  - Padilla, Dan, 2007 July 27 (Box 2)
  - Peters, Duane, 2001 May 4 (Box 2)
  - Potential Johns, 2008 March 18 (Box 2)
  - Propagandhi: Chris Hannah, 2000 November 8 (Box 2)
  - Quint, Al, 2001 October 20 (Box 2)
  - Randy, 2004 February 13 (Box 2)
    Troubadour, West Hollywood, CA
  - Reagan SS, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Riverboat Gamblers, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Riverboat Gamblers: Mike Wiebe, 2004 May 7 (Box 2)
    Phone interview for Thrasher Magazine.
  - Rivethead, 2003 June 14 (Box 2)
  - Selby Tigers, 2000 December 5 (Box 2)
    Kin Tiki bar, played at Skrappy's, Tuscon, AZ.
  - Shark Pants, 2009 February 7 (Box 2)
    San Pedro, CA
  - The Shemps, 2004 January 16 (Box 2)
  - Skulls, 2003 February (Box 2)
    Linda's Doll Hut, Anaheim, CA. Interview for Thrasher Magazine.
  - Skulls: additional info, circa 2003 (Box 2)
  - Smalltown, 2004 September 7 (Box 2)
    Oskarshamn, Sweden
  - Smith, Winston, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Smogtown, 2001 September 29 (Box 2)
    Skate park
  - Smogtown, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Smoke on Fire, 2005 April 25 (Box 2)
    Date handwritten on insert is 9/30/04.
  - Snakepit, Ben, 2004 March 21 (Box 2)
  - Snuff, 2000s (Box 2)
  - The Soviettes, 2003 June 12 (Box 2)
    Minneapolis, MN
  - Stanton, Scott, 2005 August 8 (Box 3)
  - The Starvations, 2002 March 16 (Box 2)
    Outside of The Garage, Los Angeles, CA
  - The Starvations, 2000s (Box 3)
  - The Sitches, 2003 March 28 (Box 2)
    The Gypsy Lounge, Lake Forest, CA
  - Strike Anywhere, 2002 June 8 (Box 2)
    The Palace, Hollywood, CA
  - Super Chinchilla Rescue MIssion, 2001 July 28 (Box 2)
    En route to the Recreation Station, NJ
  - Superchunk, 2000s (Box 2)
  - Sweet J.A.P., 2003 August 12 (Box 2)
  - Swingin' Utters, 2000s (Box 3)
  - This Is My First, 2004 November 21 (Box 3)
    Anaheim, CA
  - Throw Rag, 2001 July 19 (Box 3)
  - The Thumbs, 2000s (Box 3)
  - Tiltwheel: Davey Quinn (Davey Tiltwheel), 2001 August 1 (Box 3)
    Dubuque, IA, tour
  - Tiltwheel: Davey Quinn (Davey Tiltwheel), 2009 February 26 (Box 3)
    Insert is labeled 1 of 2 but second tape not present in collection.
  - Tiltwheel, 2009 February 28 (Box 3)
  - Tiltwheel: Paul Trash and J Wang, 2009 (Box 3)
  - Tiltwheel, 2000s (Box 3)
    Handwritten on B side of tape: D4- just a minute
  - The Tim Version, 2005 January 25 (Box 3)
  - Toys That Kill, 2002 January 12 (Box 3)
    Newland Apartment
  - Turbonegro, 2003 March 3 (Box 3)
  - The Tyrades, 2004 June 30 (Box 3)
  - The Underground Railroad to Candyland (URTC), 2009 May 14 (Box 3)
  - Vachss, Andrew, 2000s (Box 3)
  - Vallejo, Mike, 2000s (Box 3)
    3 microcassettes.
  - Weeks, Grier (PROTECT), 2004 February 26 (Box 3)
  - Western Addiction, 2001 November 3 (Box 3)
  - Yemin, Dan, 2000s (Box 3)
  - Young Offenders, 2009 December 5 (Box 3)
    San Francisco, CA
- Razorcake Fanzine Issues, 2001-2016
  Published issues of Razorcake fanzine from its inception up until March 2016 issue. Collection is missing no. 47.
  - Razorcake: No. 1-19, 2001-2004 (Box 4)
  - Razorcake: No. 20-36, 2004-2007 (Box 5)
  - Razorcake: No. 37-55, 2007-2010 (Box 6)
    Missing issue number 47, December 2008/January 2009
  - Razorcake: No. 56-73, 2010-2013 (Box 7)
  - Razorcake: No. 74-90, 2013-2016 (Box 8)
- Memorabilia and Ephemera, 1989-2015
  - Punk t-shirts, 1989-2015 (Box 9, Box 10, Box 11)
    59 t-shirts with silk-screened logos of bands, record labels, record stores, and festivals, including Corrosion of Conformity, Thrasher, AwesomeFest, and Jay Reatard's early project, The Reatards. Also included are several Razorcake shirts, notably the shirt worn by Todd Taylor on the cover of his book Born to Rock.
  - Flight jacket, circa 1990s (Box 12)
    Black flight jacket with patches sewn on.
  - Book Your Own Fucking Life: No. 7, 10, 1999-2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Razorcake poster, 2009 (Box 13)